hometogo.com 2019-12-06

# Legal, Terms and Conditions, & Privacy Policy | HomeToGo

##  Privacy Policy Regarding the Use of Data on hometogo.com 

Data privacy is a matter of trust, and your trust matters to HomeToGo. It is therefore important to us that your personal data is protected and that its collection, processing and use in relation to HomeToGo's services in our app and on our website hometogo.com complies with the law. In this Policy, we want to tell you about how we collect and use data, in order to give you an overview of how your personal data will be used.

1. Overview

The following Privacy Policy contains information about the way and extent to which personal data is processed by HomeToGo. Personal data is information that can be directly or indirectly attributed to or associated with you personally, such as your name or your email address.

2. Name and contact details of the controller responsible for processing and the company's Data Protection Officer

This Privacy Policy applies to the data processing performed by HomeToGo GmbH, Perleberger Str. 42a, 10559 Berlin (the "controller", hereinafter "HomeToGo"), to be contacted at [info@hometogo.com](mailto:info@hometogo.com), and for the following website or application: www.hometogo.com.

The company Data Protection Officer of HomeToGo can be reached at [privacy@hometogo.com](mailto:privacy@hometogo.com) (Waterside DS GmbH, Bergstr. 28, 22095 Hamburg, Germany).

3. The purposes for which data is processed, the legal basis and legitimate interests pursued by HomeToGo or a third party, as well as categories of recipients

3.1. Accessing our website/application

When you access our website/application, the browser used on your device automatically sends information to the server of our website/application and temporarily stores it in what is known as a log file. We have no control over this. The following information will also be collected without any action on your part and be stored until it is automatically deleted:

  * the IP address of the requesting internet-enabled device
  * the date and time of access
  * the name and URL of the retrieved file
  * the website/application from which access took place (the Referrer URL)
  * the browser you are using, and potentially the operating system of your internet-enabled computer, as well as the name of your access provider
  * the device used (e.g., a desktop computer or a smartphone)
  * the language of the browser you are using

The legal basis for processing your IP address is Article 6 (1) (f) of the General Data Processing Regulation (GDPR). Our legitimate interest is based on the purposes of data collection listed below. We would like to point out that we are unable to draw any direct conclusions regarding your identity from the data that is collected, and that we refrain from doing so.

We use the IP address of your device and the other data listed above for the following purposes:

  * ensuring that a trouble-free connection is established
  * ensuring the comfortable use of our website/application
  * the evaluation of system security and stability

The data will be erased as soon as it is no longer required for the purpose of its initial collection. In the case of data collection to enable making the website available, this is the case when the respective session ends. The data is stored in log-files for a period of up to 6 weeks and is then deleted automatically so that it is no longer possible to allocate the user.

We also use what are known as cookies for our website/application, as well as tracking tools, targeting methods and social media plug-ins. The exact procedures used and how your data are used for this purpose are explained in more detail below.

3.2. Creating and using a user account; bookings, booking inquiries and HomeToGo Money-Back Guarantee

3.2.1. Creating an account

When you create a user account with us, we process personal data in the following alternative manner:

  * when logging in using Google (social login), your Gmail address and the information transmitted from your Google account (names, profile picture, link to your Google account and top-level domain, gender and hosted domain)
  * when logging in using Facebook (social login: Facebook Connect), your email address and the public information from your Facebook account (names, profile picture, age range, gender, language, country and other public information)
  * when logging in using your email, your email address

Likewise, a user account is created when you enter your email address and then make a booking or booking inquiry through our website (see section 3.2.2.), or if you choose the HomeToGo Money-Back Guarantee (see section 3.3.). These services require the setup of a user account for technical reasons, storing email address, name and travel dates.

Each time you log in, technical information is stored about your device and your browser, as well as information about your searches. This helps us to improve your overall user experience on the website, as well as the overall services.

The legal basis for this is Article 6 (1) (b) and (f) of the GDPR. You provide us with data based on the contractual relationship between you and us. Our legitimation is also derived from the protection of your identity and the prevention of fraudulent activity.

We will delete the collected data no later than your termination of our platform’s usage contract.

3.2.2. Bookings and booking inquiries

We do not offer travel services ourselves. Rather, we enable you to book travel services offered by our partners.

When a booking inquiry is received, we collect the following data solely in order to forward it to our partners:

  * the desired arrival and departure dates
  * your first and last name
  * the number of guests
  * your email address
  * (optionally) your message to the landlord

When you make a booking, we collect the following data solely in order to forward it to our partners:

  * the arrival and departure dates
  * your first and last name
  * the number of guests
  * your address
  * your email address
  * your phone number
  * (optionally) selected extras
  * the payment method, whereby payment processing is performed by Datatrans payment service (Datatrans AG, Kreuzbühlstrasse 26, 8008 Zurich, Switzerland), with whom we have concluded a data processing agreement

With the exception of the email address, name and travel dates, all of the aforementioned data will be deleted by us after it has been forwarded to the respective partner.

The collection of the aforementioned data and its transmission to our partners is a pre-contractual step that is required to enter into the contract with your respective partner (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR).

3.3. Creating an account with HomeToGo Money-Back Guarantee

If you choose the HomeToGo Money-Back Guarantee, a user account is automatically created. The HomeToGo Money-Back Guarantee is an insurance provided by AWP P&C S.A. (Allianz Global Assistance, hereinafter “insurer”) with whom we have concluded a group insurance contract.

To record you and your fellow travelers as beneficiaries, the following data are collected and passed on to the insurance intermediary, Kasko Germany UG:

  * the arrival and departure dates
  * your first and last name
  * your address
  * your email address
  * your phone number
  * booking date
  * booking number

We only store the data for the purpose of processing the insurance contract for the duration of the insurer’s contractual obligation towards you as the beneficiary. Legal basis is Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR.

3.4. Social logins (logging in with Facebook or Google)

3.4.1. Facebook Connect

When you log in through Facebook Connect, a direct connection is created to the servers at Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). Facebook detects that you have used your login information from HomeToGo as part of this process.

If you have expressly given your consent to Facebook pursuant to Article 6 (1) (a) of the GDPR, your personal data will be transmitted to us as part of the registration process via the social login. We use the following information from the transmitted data, which is stored by us until it is automatically deleted:

  * your email address
  * your Facebook profile name (first and last name)
  * the profile and wallpaper image you use on Facebook
  * your age group (over 18, over 21 years old)
  * a link to your Facebook account
  * your gender
  * the top-level domain of your logged-in Facebook account
  * the time zone in which you are on Facebook

This data is used to

  * identify you as our contractual partner
  * set up your user account
  * check the entered data for plausibility

The legal basis for the use of this data is Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR. Using this data enables us to fulfill our contractual obligations which arise from our Terms of Service (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR). We will delete the collected data no later than your termination of our platform’s usage contract.

You can block the connection within your Facebook account.

Please refer to Facebook’s privacy policy for details regarding the purpose and scope of the data collection and further processing and use of the data by your service provider, as well as regarding your associated rights and the settings options you can use to protect your privacy (<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>).

3.4.2. Logging in with Google

When you log in with Google by selecting "G continue with Google", a direct connection is established with the servers of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google detects that you have used your login information from HomeToGo as part of this process. We do not obtain your Google Account information. Google then informs you that data from your Google Account will be made available to us and indicates the specific data in question.

Registration with and the use of Google are governed by Google's privacy policy and terms of service (<https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl>).

If you have expressly given your consent to Google pursuant to Article 6 (1) (a) of the GDPR, your personal data will be transmitted to us as part of the registration process via Google. We use the following information from the transmitted data, which is stored by us until it is automatically deleted:

  * your email address
  * your name on your Google account (first and last name)
  * the profile image (or the avatar) used on Google
  * a link to your Google account
  * your gender
  * the top-level domain of your logged-in Google account
  * the user domain you manage on Google (hosted domain, HD)

This data is used to

  * enable us to identify you as our contractual partner
  * set up your user account
  * check the entered data for plausibility

The legal basis for the use of this data is Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR. Using this data enables us to fulfill our contractual obligations which arise from our Terms of Service (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR). We will delete the collected data no later than your termination of our platform’s usage contract.

You can block the connection within your Google account.

Please refer to Google’s privacy policy for details regarding the purpose and scope of the data collection and further processing and use of the data by Google, as well as regarding your associated rights and the settings options you can use to protect your privacy (<https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl>).

3.4.3. Email service

We use the SendGrid service of Twilio / SendGrid, Inc., 1801 California Street, Suite 500, Denver, Colorado 80202, USA, to send some emails (booking and inquiry confirmations and notifications, as well as advertising). Your email address and your first and last name will be processed to personalize the emails sent. A data processing relationship is in place with Twilio / SendGrid.

The legal basis for this is the fulfillment of our contractual obligations pursuant to Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR or the consent pursuant to Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR that you may revoke at any time. The lawfulness of the data processing already carried out remains unaffected by the revocation. There is a legitimate interest to process data through Twilio / SendGrid pursuant to Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

Further information can be found in Twilio / SendGrid’s Privacy Policy (<https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/>). 

3.5. Data processing for advertising purposes

3.5.1. Newsletter

On our website, we offer you the opportunity to sign up for our newsletter. You can revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. To do so, you need only click the unsubscribe link.

3.5.2. Product recommendations

We send you emails which contain product recommendations. You will receive these product recommendations regardless of whether you have subscribed to a newsletter. We do so in order to provide you with information about products from our offerings that may interest you based on your recent searches.

If you do not want to receive product recommendations from us, you can let us know at any time. You can find our contact details under section 2. Naturally, you will also find an unsubscribe link in every email.

3.5.3. Interest-based advertising

In order for you to receive information that is likely to be of interest to you, we categorize your user profile. To do so, we use information about your searches to customize the newsletter articles and promotional emails we send you. The goal is to send you advertising that is oriented towards your actual needs and to avoid sending unnecessary advertising.

The legal basis for the aforementioned processing is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Processing existing customer data this way for advertising purposes is deemed to be a legitimate interest.

3.5.4 Push notifications

In our application we offer the possibility to activate push notifications which include short information on relevant topics and news about our services and may be displayed even if you are not using the application. If you allow or activate push notifications, a token will be assigned to your device. The token is an encrypted identifier and is used for the technical implementation of push notifications. We use the services of Accengage S.A., 31 rue du 4 Septembre, 75 002 Paris, France, to send and control push notifications. Data is collected and transmitted (push ID, IP address, access times, advertising identifier if applicable, location data if applicable). In addition, data about the use of the push notifications (such as opening rate or display duration) is collected and stored for improvement and customization of our services. Accengage will only receive the relevant data with your consent. You can revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. You can activate or deactivate push notifications at any time in the settings of your device. Further details and information can be found in the Accengage Privacy Policy at <https://www.accengage.com/privacy-policy/>.

The legal basis for the processing of your data in the context of push notifications is Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR, for the analysis for customized services it is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Your data will only be stored for the duration of the use of the push notification services.

3.5.5. Right to object

 _You have the right, at any time and at no charge, to object to data processing for the aforementioned purposes, separately for each respective communication channel, and with effect for the future. To do so, you need only send an email to_[ _info@hometogo.com_](mailto:info@hometogo.com) _or send a letter to the HomeToGo address mentioned in section 2 above._

In the event that you object, the relevant contact address will be blocked for further promotional processing. We point out that, in exceptional cases, advertising material may temporarily continue to be sent to you even after your objection has been received. This is due to technical reasons related to the lead time required for advertisements and does not mean that your objection will not be observed by us. Thank you for your understanding.

3.6. Cookies – general information 

We use cookies on our website on the basis of Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Our interest in optimizing our website is deemed to be legitimate within the meaning of the aforementioned provision.

Cookies are small files that your browser automatically creates and that are stored on your device (laptop, tablet, smartphone, etc.) when you visit our website or use our app. Cookies do not harm your device, do not contain viruses, Trojans or other malicious software. The information stored in the cookie is tied to the specific device used. However, this does not mean that we are immediately aware of your identity. In part, cookies are used to make the use of our service more pleasant for you. For example, we use what are known as session cookies to detect that you have already visited individual pages on our website or that you have already logged in to your user account. These are automatically deleted after you leave our website. In addition, to ensure user-friendliness we also use temporary cookies, which are stored on your device for a specific period of time. If you visit our website again to use our services, it is automatically detected that you have already visited us, as well as what information you entered and the settings you used, so that you do not have to reenter them.

If you already have an account and are logged in or activate the "Stay logged in" feature, the information stored in cookies will be added to your user account.

On the other hand, we use cookies to statistically record the use of our website, to optimize our services, and to display information tailored to your specific needs. These cookies enable us to automatically detect that you have previously visited us when you return to our website. These cookies are automatically deleted after a defined period of time. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. However, you can configure your browser so that no cookies are stored on your computer or to make sure that a message always appears before a new cookie is created. However, disabling cookies completely may mean that you will not be able to use all the features of our website. The storage period of cookies depends on their purpose and therefore varies.

3.7. Analytical tools

In order to customize and continuously optimize our websites in line with users’ needs, we deploy tools on the basis of Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR which permit us to analyze the use of our website.

3.7.1. Google Analytics 

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google. In doing so, pseudonymized usage profiles are created and cookies are used. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website, e.g.

  * browser type/version
  * operating system used
  * Referrer URL (the previously visited page)
  * hostname of the accessing computer (IP address)
  * time of server request

is transmitted to a Google server in the US and stored there. Google complies with the Privacy Policy of the US Privacy Shield and is registered with the U.S. Department of Commerce's US Privacy Shield Program. In addition, we have entered into a data processing agreement for the use of Google Analytics. Under this agreement, Google assures that Google processes data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and ensures the protection of the data subject's rights.

The information is used to evaluate the use of the website, to compile reports on the activity on the website, and to provide other services related to the use of the website and internet usage for the purposes of market research and to customize the design of these websites in line with the needs of users. This information may also be transferred to third parties if required by law or if third parties are contracted to process this data. Under no circumstances will your IP address be combined with any other data from Google. The IP addresses are anonymized, which means that it is not possible to identify specific individuals (“IP masking”).

3.7.2. Google Tag Manager

We use the Google Tag Manager. This Google service allows website tags to be managed through an interface. Only tags are implemented, i.e. no cookies are set and no personal data is collected. The Tag Manager triggers other tags that may themselves collect data. Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If deactivation has been done at the domain or cookie level, it will apply to all tracking tags implemented with Google Tag Manager. More information can be found in the Google Tag Manager use policy: <https://www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.html>.

3.7.3. New Relic

To perform accessibility and performance monitoring for our servers, we use the "New Relic" web analytics service provided by New Relic Inc., 188 Spear Street, Suite 1200, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA. Using pseudonymized usage data, technical performance data (e.g., response and load times) is measured and analyzed to improve our server performance. Further details and information can be found in the New Relic Privacy Policy at <https://newrelic.com/privacy/>.

3.7.4. Snowplow

We use the Snowplow open source web analytics service provided by Snowplow Analytics Limited, 32-38 Scrutton Street, London, EC2A 4RQ, United Kingdom. Cookies are used as part of this. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website, e.g.

  * browser type/version
  * operating system used
  * Referrer URL (the previously visited page)
  * hostname of the accessing computer (IP address)
  * time of server request
  * search queries and filter settings
  * clicks on the website

is transmitted to a HomeToGo server in Frankfurt and stored there.

The information is used to evaluate the use of the website, to compile reports on the activity on the website, and to provide other services related to the use of the website and internet usage for the purposes of market research and to customize the design in line with the needs of users.

3.7.5. Adjust

In our app, we use the analytics service of Adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 37A, 10405 Berlin, Germany. The analytics service is implemented in our app via a development environment (SDK - Software Developer Kit). The information generated by the development environment, e.g.

  * hashed (anonymized) IP address
  * mobile identifiers such as the Advertising ID for iOS (IDFA) or the Google Advertising ID
  * installation and initial opening of an app on your mobile device
  * your interaction within an app (e.g., in-app purchases, registration),
  * viewed and clicked ads

is collected and used by Adjust GmbH to evaluate the use of the app, to compile performance reports on app activity, and to provide other services related to the use of the app for purposes of market research and customization of the app. Under no circumstances will the collected data be combined with other data that Adjust obtains via other apps.

You can find more information about Adjust's privacy policy here: <https://www.adjust.com/privacy-policy/>. You can object to tracking by Adjust at any time within the "Opt-out" section of Adjust's Privacy Policy. To do this, you must select the device for which you do not want Adjust to perform tracking and specify your Device Identifier. Behavior tracking from apps that use Adjust will then be immediately removed on your device.

3.7.6. TrackJS

We use the services of TrackJS LLC. TrackJS allows us to analyze technical errors in JavaSkript, so that we can check and improve the quality of our website and app. More information can be found in TrackJS privacy policy: <https://trackjs.com/privacy/>.

3.7.7. Videobeat

We use the Videobeat analytics software by Videobeat Networks GmbH, Rathausstr. 4, 20095 Hamburg, Germany, for the analysis of television and online marketing activities. Traffic on our website is monitored via a tracking pixel.

Pixels, also known as tracking pixels, are small 1x1-pixel GIF files that can be hidden e.g. in graphics or in e-mails when visiting a website. Pixels do not damage your device and do not contain viruses, Trojans or other malware.

Through the pixel, IP addresses already collected anonymously are stored together with other data (e.g., operating system or device) in a database. Neither we, nor Videobeat can use that data to identify a concrete person . The information in the database is for the purpose of analysis and evaluation for the production of media plans.

Videobeat’s Privacy Policy can be found here: <https://www.videobeat.net/us/data-privacy-policy/>. You can object to the collection of your data by Videobeat at any time by clicking here: [https://pa.videobeat.net/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en](https://pa.videobeat.net/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en).

3.7.8. Matomo

Additionally, we use the Matomo (formerly Piwik) open source web analytics service provided by InnoCraft Ltd., 150 Willis St, 6011 Wellington, New Zealand (“Matomo”). For this, cookies are used to enable analysis the use of our website. From this data, pseudonymized user profiles can be created and analyzed. The information generated by the cookie, such as your browser and pseudonymized IP address, is processed on our servers. The information generated by the cookie in the pseudonymous user profile is not used to personally identify you and is not combined with your personal data.

More information on data protection when using Matomo can be found here: <https://matomo.org/privacy-policy/>. There you can object to website tracking via “Opt-out“.

3.8. Targeting

The targeting measures listed below and used by us are implemented on the basis of Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Targeting is used to perform targeted advertising. Through the targeting measures we use, we want to make sure that advertisements which are geared to your interests are displayed on your devices.

3.8.1. Double Click

On our website, information used for the optimization of advertisements is collected and evaluated using cookies (see section 3.6.). To do this, we use Google's targeting technologies (Double Click). These technologies enable us to provide you with customized, interest-based advertising. The cookies used provide e.g. information regarding which of our products you are interested in. Based on this information, we can also display services on third-party websites that are specifically oriented towards your interests you have shown through your previous user behavior. The collection and evaluation of your user behavior takes place exclusively in pseudonymized manner and does not enable us to identify you. In particular, the information is not combined with personally identifiable information about you.

The cookie is automatically deleted after 30 days.

You can also set preferences for the display of interest-based advertising through the Google Ads Settings Manager (<https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl>).

For more information and the privacy policy regarding advertising and Google, please refer to Google’s Privacy Policy and Terms of Service (<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl>).

3.8.2. Google AdWords

HomeToGo uses Google's AdWords service, which uses conversion tracking to measure the effectiveness of individual ads, offers and features. For this, a cookie is set as soon as you click on a Google ad. This cookie does not personally identify you, but rather makes it possible to determine whether you return to the page with the specific offer during the 30-day period in which the cookie is valid.

Each AdWords advertiser receives a different cookie. As a result, cookies cannot be tracked via the website of AdWords advertisers. The information obtained using the conversion cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. We track the total number of users who have clicked on an ad and were redirected to the website with a conversion-tracking tag.

You can permanently prevent the storage of the Google conversion cookie by setting your browser software accordingly. Google's privacy policy on conversion tracking can be found here: <https://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html>.

3.8.3. Google Dynamic Remarketing

We use the features of Google Dynamic Remarketing with the cross-device features of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick.

This feature allows us to link the advertising audiences created with Google Dynamic Remarketing to the cross-device features of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick. In this way, interest-based, personalized advertising messages that have been customized for you based on your past usage and browsing behavior on a device (e.g., smartphone) may also be displayed on another device you use (e.g., tablet or PC).

If you have given the appropriate consent to Google, Google will link your web and app browsing history with your Google Account for this purpose. That way, the same personalized advertising messages can appear on any device you use to sign in to your Google Account.

To support this feature, Google Analytics collects Google-authenticated IDs of users who are temporarily linked to our Google Analytics data to define and create audiences for cross-device ad promotion.

You can permanently opt out of cross-device remarketing/targeting by turning off personalized advertising in your Google Account. To do so, follow this link: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl>.

For more information, as well as the provisions regarding data privacy, please see the Google Privacy Policy at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl>.

3.8.4. Google AdSense

On our website, we use Google AdSense for displaying advertisements. In this way we can show you advertisements that may be of interest to you. These advertisements can be recognized by the reference "Google Ads". To do this, Google uses web beacons and cookies (see section 3.6.). The information generated by cookies and web beacons about the use of the website (including your IP address) and delivery of advertising formats is transmitted to a Google server in the US and stored there. Google may share this information with third parties.

We have enabled third-party Google AdSense ads. The data may be transferred to third parties (named at <https://support.google.com/dfp_sb/answer/94149>).

You can prevent Google AdSense from installing cookies by disabling interest-based ads on Google via the link <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl>.

For more information, as well as the provisions regarding data privacy, please see the Google Privacy Policy at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl>.

3.8.5. Google AdMob

We use Google AdMob to display ads in the HomeToGo app. Google uses the Apple "Advertising Identifier" (hereafter “Apple Ad-ID”) for advertising control in the app. A pseudonymized user profile is created under the Apple Ad-ID so that the user can be matched to different advertising segments on the Apple advertising platform in order to be able to display interest-based advertising.

The Apple Ad-ID is a pseudonym that prevents personal plain data from being disclosed to Google. The Apple Ad-ID is transmitted to a Google server in the US and stored there.

You can prevent the use of the Apple Ad-ID by clicking on "No Ad-Tracking" under "Privacy/Advertising" in your system settings. Alternatively, you can also click “Reset Ad ID” to generate a new, randomly chosen Apple Ad ID and thus prevent a profile from being generated.

3.8.6. Criteo

Pixel technologies (see section 3.7.5.) from Criteo SA, 32 Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France ("Criteo") collect and store data for marketing and optimization purposes. Together with Criteo, we determine the purposes and means of processing and are therefore jointly responsible for processing.

The pixels send your IP address, the Referrer URL of the visited website, the time when the pixel was viewed, the browser used and previously set cookie information to a web server. This data can be used to create usage profiles under a pseudonym.

Criteo's pixel technologies allow us to evaluate our advertising campaigns and advertising content. Using an algorithm, Criteo analyzes surfing behavior and can then display targeted product recommendations as personalized advertising banners on other websites (“publishers”). You can find more information about Criteo’s technology in Criteo’s Privacy Policy (<https://www.criteo.com/privacy/>).

Using Criteo will load additional pixels from contractual partners with whom Criteo works. An overview of all publishers and networks that load pixels can be found at <https://www.criteo.com/privacy/criteo-works-with-the-following-platforms/>. The data collected with Criteo technology will not be used to determine the personal identity of the website visitor unless agreed to separately by the data subject. Any use of data other than that described above or transfer to third parties is excluded.

Most browsers accept pixels automatically. You can use the appropriate tools or browser add-ons to prevent the use of pixels on our website (for example, by using the "AdBlock" add-on for the Firefox browser).

You can also object to the pseudonymous analysis of your surfing behavior by us at any time. For instructions on disabling Criteo's service, please visit the following Criteo link: <https://www.criteo.com/privacy/>.

Please note that if you opt out of displaying personalized ads from Criteo and other affiliates, you will still receive advertisements, however these will be less tailored to your interests/browsing habits.

3.8.7. Bing Ads

We use Bing Universal Event Tracking (UET) from Microsoft Bing Ads. This is a service of Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052, USA ("Microsoft"). This allows us to track user activity on our website when users reach our website through advertisements from Bing Ads.

If you reach our website via a Bing Ads advertisement, a cookie will be placed on your computer (see section 3.6.). A Bing UET tag is integrated into our website. This is a code that is used to store data about the use of the website in connection with the cookie. Among others, this includes the time spent on the website, which areas of the website were accessed, and what ads brought users to the website. Information about your identity is not collected.

This information is transmitted to Microsoft servers in the US and stored there for a maximum of 180 days.

More information on Bing Ads’ analytical services can be found on Bing Ads website (<https://help.bingads.microsoft.com/#apex/3/en/53056/2>). For more information about Microsoft’s privacy practice, please see Microsoft’s Privacy Policy (<https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement>).

3.8.8. Outbrain

On our website, we use technology from the service provider Outbrain Inc., 39 West 13th Street, New York, NY 10011, USA (Outbrain, Outbrain Widgets, Outbrain Pixel). This technology enables us to use pixels (see section 3.7.5.) and cookies (see section 3.6.) to offer further content that may also be of interest to you within our website or on third-party websites ("retargeting"). The recommendations integrated by Outbrain are determined on the basis of your previously read content. The content is technically controlled and delivered by Outbrain automatically.

Display takes place on a pseudonymous basis. When selecting appropriate content, the cookie uses information about the source of the device, the type of browser and your IP address, which is fully anonymized by removing the last octet.

More information about Outbrain's Privacy Policy can be found here: <https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy#privacy-policy>. You may opt-out of Outbrain's use of tracking to display interest-based recommendations via the “Opt out” field within Outbrain's Privacy Policy. Please note that you must separately set the opt-out in each device you use to access our website. After objecting, you will continue to be offered interesting additional content, however this will no longer be based on your previous usage behavior on our websites.

3.8.9. Taboola

Our website uses technologies from Taboola Inc., 28 West 23rd St., New York, NY 10010, USA ("Taboola"). Taboola uses cookies (see section 3.6.) that determine which content you use and which of our pages you visit (conversion tracking). The cookie enables us to create pseudonymous usage profiles by collecting device-related data as well as log data, and enables us to recommend content that matches your personal interests. This permits us to individually customize our offerings for you. These usage profiles cannot be used to establish your identity.

You can find more information about Taboola and the ability to disable the Taboola cookie here: <https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy>.

3.8.10. Facebook Custom Audiences

In addition, we also use Facebook Custom Audiences. Facebook Custom Audiences is a Facebook marketing service. It allows us to display personalized and interest-based advertising on Facebook to certain groups of pseudonymized visitors to our website who also use Facebook.

A Facebook Custom Audience pixel is integrated into our website. This is a Java Script code used to store non-personal information about your use of the site. This includes your IP address, the browser you are using, and the source and destination pages. This information is transmitted to Facebook servers in the United States. There, an automatic check is performed to see if you have saved a Facebook cookie. The Facebook cookie automatically determines whether you belong to the relevant target group for us. If you belong to the target group, we will show you relevant ads on Facebook. You will not be personally identified by us or by Facebook as part of this process.

You may object to the use of the Custom Audiences service on the Facebook website (<https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences>). After logging in to your Facebook account, you will be taken to the settings for Facebook ads.

For more information on privacy on Facebook, see Facebook’s Privacy Policy (<https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>).

3.8.11. RTB House

On our website, we use technology from RTB House S.A., 61/101 Złota Street, 00-819 Warsaw, Poland. This technology enables us to use pixels (see section 3.7.5.) and cookies (see section 3.6.) to offer further content that may also be of interest to you within our website or on third-party websites ("retargeting"). Cookies are used as part of this process. The recommendations integrated by RTB House are determined on the basis of your previously read content. The content is technically controlled and delivered by RTB House automatically. Display takes place on a pseudonymous basis.

The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website, such as browser type/version, operating system used, Referrer URL (the previously visited page), time of server request is transmitted to RTB House’s server and stored there.

You can find more information on RTB House's privacy policy here: <https://www.rtbhouse.com/privacy/>. You may object to RTB House's tracking to display interest-based advertising at any time via the opt-out box within RTB House's Privacy Policy. Please note that you must separately set the opt-out cookie in each device you use to access our website. After objecting, you will continue to be offered interesting additional content, however this will no longer be based on your previous usage behavior on our websites.

3.8.12. Airbnb promotional content

Our partner Airbnb Ireland UC ("Airbnb") uses tracking codes (hyperlinks and cookies, see section 3.6.) to collect information when you click on Airbnb promotional content on our website. This information includes

  * the hostname of the accessing computer (IP address)
  * browser type/version
  * operating system used
  * type of device used (e.g., smartphone or desktop) and user ID
  * location (country, region) and day of the server request.

Airbnb uses the technology to monitor, analyze and report on the performance, operation and effectiveness of Airbnb advertisements on the website. Airbnb uses a third party service provider to deliver and operate this technology on Airbnb’s behalf. Airbnb shares information obtained via this technology with HomeToGo for reporting purposes.

For Airbnb’s contact details, further information about Airbnb's use of the technology and of personal data, as well as information about your rights and choices in this context, see Airbnb's Privacy Policy (<https://www.airbnb.co.uk/terms/privacy_policy>) and Cookie Policy (<https://www.airbnb.co.uk/terms/cookie_policy>).

3.8.13. Intent Media

On our website, we use technologies of Intent Media Inc., 2 Riding House St, London W1W 7FA, United Kingdom. Intent Media uses cookies (see section 3.6.) and web beacons to collect IP addresses, browser type, referrer URL, time of access and number of clicks with the purpose of targeting and placement of advertisements on our website. You can find further information on the technology here: <https://intentmedia.com/privacy-policy/>.

Information on your use of our website collected via cookie is transmitted to Intent Media servers, stored there and analyzed to personalize advertising on the website and other websites you visit.

You can object to Intent Media’s tracking by displaying interest-based recommendations at any time by clicking this link: <http://intentmedia.com/opt-out/>.

3.8.14. Clicktripz

On our website, we also use services by Clicktripz, 1112 Ocean Drive, CA 90266 Manhattan Beach, USA. Clicktripz collects and processes user’s travel criteria and shopping behavior through the use of cookies (see section 3.6.) and other means to provide relevant offers from partnering travel websites.

You can find more information in Clicktripz’s privacy policy: <http://www.clicktripz.com/privacy_policy.php>.

3.8.15. Ad Up

Technology from Ad Up, a service provider of Axel Springer Teaser Ad GmbH, Axel-Springer-Str. 65, 10969 Berlin, Germany, is also integrated on our website. Ad Up uses cookies for conversion tracking, the evaluation of the effectiveness of advertisements and keywords. By collecting anonymized and/or pseudonymous data, Ad Up can display advertisements according to your interests for a certain period of time.

More information can be found in Ad Up’s privacy policy here: <https://www.adup-tech.com/en/privacy>. You can deactivate Ad Up in your browser by clicking the button “activate opt-out cookie” there.

3.8.16. BingAds Services

On our website, we use BingAds Services by Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited, One Microsoft Place, South County Business Park, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, D18 P521, Ireland, for displaying advertisements. In this way we can show you advertisements that may be of interest to you. These advertisements can be recognized by the note “Ads by Microsoft” or a similar reference. Microsoft uses web beacons and cookies (see section 3.6). The information generated by cookies and web beacons about the use of the website (including you IP address and device ID) and delivery of advertising formats is transmitted to a Microsoft server in Ireland and the US and stored there.

For more information, as well as the provisions regarding data privacy, please see the Microsoft Privacy Policy at <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement>. There it is explained how you can object to the interest-based advertisement via opt-out.

3.8.17. Other third parties

Besides, we also engage a third party partner for the purpose of identifying users and delivering to them interest-based content and advertisements. We may share information about you with our partners such as a non-human-readable form of your email or other identifier to ensure the security of your information. Our partners also may collect information directly from your device, such as your IP address, device ID, and information about your browser or operating system; may combine our personal and non-personal information about you with information from other sources; and may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser.

You can opt-out of these partners’ services in the following manner:

To opt-out of BouncePilot’s services, please go to <http://www.bouncepilot.com/opt-out/> . To opt out of LiveRamp’s services, please go to <https://liveramp.com/opt_out/>. To opt-out of third party cookies, please go to <http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>. To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <https://youradchoices.com/appchoices>.

3.8.18. Option to object/opt-out

 _You can prevent the targeting technologies we described by activating the appropriate cookie setting in your browser (see also section 3.6.). In addition, you have the option of deactivating preference-based advertising with the help of the preference manager available here:_[ _http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices_](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) _._

3.9. Third party websites

HomeToGo cooperates with partners (see in-detail our Terms of Service where our partners are referred to as “Providers” in section 1 (1)). Once you are redirected to a partner’s website, the terms of the respective partner apply.

Neither partners, nor intermediaries of the partner’s offers (affiliate) drop cookies or use other tracking-codes on our website. Cookies or tracking-codes are used after the redirection, upon which HomeToGo has no influence. The following affiliate services are used:

  * Performance advertising network by AWIN AG, Eichhornstr. 3, 10785 Berlin, Germany; you can find AWIN’s privacy policy here: <https://www.awin.com/gb/legal/privacy-policy-gb>.
  * Performance Horizon Group Ltd, West One, Forth Banks, Newcastle upon Tyne NE1 3PA, United Kingdom; you can find Performance Horizon’s privacy policy here: <https://performancehorizon.com/privacy-policy>.
  * CJ Affiliate, Commission Junction LLC, 530 East Montecito St., Santa Barbara, CA 93103, USA; you can find CJ’s privacy policy here: <https://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy>.

4\. Third party services and plugins

4.1. Google Maps

We use Google Maps API for displaying interactive maps directly on our website and to enable the simplified use of map functionality. Your IP address is transmitted and stored on one of Google’s servers in the US for the usage of Google Maps functionality (see section 3.7.1 regarding the US Privacy Shield). Legal basis is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. 

Please see the Terms of Service for Google Maps here: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/help/terms_maps.html>. You can find further information on data privacy in Google’s Privacy Policy here: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.

4.2. Google Fonts

On our website we use fonts (“Google Fonts”) provided by Google. For this your browser loads the required font into your browser cache when our website is opened. This is necessary so that the browser can display a visually improved version of our texts. If your browser does not support this feature, a default font will be used by your computer for display. The integration of these fonts is completed by a server call, usually a Google server in the USA. This will communicate to the server that you have visited this website.

When the page is accessed, cookies are not sent by users to the Google Fonts API. Data transferred in connection with the pageview is sent to resource-specific domains such as fonts.googleapis.com or fonts.gstatic.com. You will not be associated with any information collected or used in connection with the parallel use of authenticated Google services, such as Gmail. You can set your browser so that the fonts from Google servers are not loaded.

HomeToGo uses Google fonts to ensure an appealing presentation of its services. The legal basis is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

Further information can be found in Google’s privacy policy (<https://policies.google.com/privacy>).

5. Group

HomeToGo is a company of the HomeToGo Group. We may share your personal data with our associated companies within the HomeToGo Group on an occasional basis. The HomeToGo Group includes all (current and future) entities that are directly or indirectly controlled by HomeToGo GmbH (“HomeToGo”) or are under common control of HomeToGo. The transfer of data within the HomeToGo Group takes place for the following purposes:

a)     Provision of our intermediary services and of our portal

b)     Provision of customer service services

c)     Sending advertising with your consent or if permitted by applicable law

d)     Analysis, optimization and improvement of our website and app

e)     Identification and investigation of fraud and illegal activities

f)      Compliance with laws and regulations

The legal basis for the transfer of data within the HomeToGo Group is Article 6 (1) (a), (b) and (f) GDPR.

In detail, the legal basis for the purposes a) and b) is Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR. Sharing this data enables us to fulfill our contractual obligations arising from our terms of service.

The legal basis for purpose c) is your explicit consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR) that you may revoke any time, or our legitimate interest to do marketing for existing customers (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR). The lawfulness of the data processing already carried out remains unaffected by the revocation.

For purposes d), e) and f), our legitimate interest derives from the improvement of our services as well as the protection of your identity and the prevention of fraudulent activities (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).

6. Contact form

We provide you with a contact form which you can use to ask us questions by entering your name and your email address. The use of the contact form is voluntary, and your data is processed in order to fulfill our contractual service obligations (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR).

The questions and the information you enter will be transferred to our ticket system. To this end, we make use of the support services of Desk.com, 1 Market Steet, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA. If you do not wish to have your data processed by Desk.com, please contact our customer service directly at [info@hometogo.com](mailto:info@hometogo.com).

7\. Feedback

We use the services of Zenloop GmbH, Pappelallee 78/79, 10437 Berlin, Germany. Zenloop allows us to collect and analyze user feedback through various channels. Zenloop collects the IP address, device and browser data, and the website from which the feedback tool is deployed.

The legal basis for this is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest is based on the purpose of optimizing the marketing of our services. Zenloop processes personal data on our behalf.

For more information, please see Zenloop’s Privacy Policy at <https://www.zenloop.com/en/legal/privacy>.

8. Your rights

8.1. Overview

In addition to the right to revoke the consent you have granted to us, you are entitled to the following further rights if the relevant legal requirements apply:

  * Right of access to information about your personal data stored with us pursuant to Article 15 GDPR
  * Right of rectification of inaccurate personal data and right to have incomplete personal data completed pursuant to Article 16 GDPR
  * Right to erasure of your personal data stored by us pursuant to Article 17 GDPR
  * Right to restriction of processing of your data pursuant to Article 18 GDPR
  * Right to data portability pursuant to Article 20 GDPR

8.2. Right to object

 _Under the conditions of Article 21 (1) GDPR, data processing can be objected to on grounds relating to the particular situation of the data subject._

The above general right of objection applies to all processing purposes described in this Privacy Policy which are based on Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Unlike the special right of objection to data processing for advertising purposes, under the GDPR we are only obliged to implement such a general objection if you give us reasons of overriding importance for this (for example, possible danger to life or health). In addition, you may also contact the supervisory authority responsible for HomeToGo, the Berlin Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information, Friedrichstr. 219, 10969 Berlin, Germany, Phone: +49 (0) 30 13889-0, Fax: +49 (0) 30 2155050, Email: [mailbox@datenschutz-berlin.de](mailto:mailbox@datenschutz-berlin.de).

Version 2 – As of the 1st of October 2019
